

Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Web Development, UI Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, PHP, CSS



Current Designation: Sr. Web Application Developer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Current Company: Stellar Information Technology

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. Current Location: Gurgaon [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, United Kingdom (UK), United States

(US)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Web Development, UI Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, PHP, CSS

Verified: Phone Number I Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## Summary

More than 7 years of experience in software development. Created front-end and back-end management systems including content management. The projects based on PHP in conjunction with various other web development technologies. PHP (core PHP, PHP with OOP), MySQL, Sqlite3, JavaScript (generic JavaScript), JQuery, JQuery UI, AJAX,XHTML / HTML and CSS are used. Designed layouts and templates for various websites and back-end panel.

To obtain a position with a progressive web application development or mobile application development company with a strong focus on creativity and problem solving. To find a position that is challenging, rewarding and provides an opportunity to expand my knowledge.

# Work Experience

#### Stellar Information Technology as Sr. Web Application Developer Nov 2016 to Till Date

- Worked on Steller Report & Auditor for Exchange Server 2.0 in Codeigniter, Ajax and SQLITE3.
- Worked on License Management project in Laravel, Ajax, Javascript and Mysql
- Worked on Steller Report & Auditor for Exchange Server in Core PHP, Javascript, Ajax and SQLITE3.
- Worked on BitRaser (Software) in PHP, Mysql, Json and Restful API.
- Worked on CRM (Customer Relationship Management) in PHP, Mysql and Jquery.
- Worked on PMS (Project Management System) in PHP, Mysql and Jquery.

#### RAINBOW APPS PRIVATE LIMITED as PHP Developer

Jul 2014 to Nov 2016

- Worked on Adjunkie in PHP, Mysql, Json and Restful API.
- Worked on Mypick app, tracking and uploading panel in PHP, Mysql, Ajax and Jquery.
- Worked on Music, video and article website and their uploading panels in PHP, Mysql, Ajax and Jquery.

#### APPSDISCOVER TECHNOLOGIES PRIVATE LIMITED as PHP Developer

Dec 2013 to Jun 2014

Worked on Affiliate Marketing Tracking Panel in PHP , Mysql and Javascript

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Arya Institute of Engineering & Technology , RTU in 2012

# IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
PHP	7.0	2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MySQL	5.4	2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
JavaScript	1.9	2019	5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
AJAX		2019	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
JQUERY	3.4	2019	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
LDAP		2019	2 Year(s)	
* NetBeans IDE 6.9 and Dreamweaver 8				
Sqlite3, HTML, CSS			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

## **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time